

Deepak Raghuwanshi

Cloud DevOps & Infrastructure Automation Engineer 9425045390 | RAGHUWANSHIDEEPAK79.DR@GMAIL.COM | in







PROFESSIONAL SKILLSET

Cloud Platforms - AWS, Azure, GCP Automation Tools - PowerShell, Core Continuous Integration (CI) - Jenkins Version Control Tools - GIT, GitLab IAAC - Terraform, Ansible Servers - Windows, Linux Ticket & ITIL - Service-Now

AWARDS QUARTELY AWARD

Best Performance | 2019 – 2020

EDUCATION

Bachelors Computer Applications Amity University | Gwalior 2015 - 2018

Minor degree in Animation Amity University | Gwalior 2017 - 2018

ABOUT ME

Hi, I am Deepak Raghuwanshi, currently working with Wipro.

I belong to Ashok Nagar a small & beautiful town in MP.

I would love to work with organization, where I can use my skills & knowledge for the growth of our organization.

CONTACT INFO









RAGHUWANSHIDEEPAK79.DR @GMAIL.COM

Qtr. No. 06, Kotwali Campus, behind new Collectorate office building, Ashok Nagar, MP-473331

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Passionate technical professional & contributor specializing in Cloud DevOps | Infrastructure Automation & integration, with a unique ability to map the needs of the business to the technology with 3.3+ Years of Experience in DevOps and Infrastructure engineering.

EXPERIENCE

Configuration Engineer | Azure Cloud DevOps Tieto | Nov 2021 - Till Date



Design & Automating Manual Process on Azure, On-Premise Infrastructure with PowerShell.

- Design & Write Terraform configurations or PowerShell Scripts for the Desired Infrastructure on Azure, AWS & GCP Cloud.
- Import Already Created Resources to Terraform state file.
- Connect with build Team & Client to understand the solution architecture & provision the infrastructure with terraform on Azure environment.
- Setting up the DevOps project, Repository, Brach polices for new
- Setup & manages azure pipelines, self-hosted Agents, CICD VMs, Networking, private Endpoint & Subnet Configurations.
- Understand & take complete handover of the solution from build team & Deploy Solution to Higher Environments.
- Create & updates wiki Documentations for the deployed feature, epic or solution.
- ❖ Assist build team to merge the feature branch with the master branch, Pull Request & code review, resolving merge conflicts & syn changes with master by rebase, cheery pickings & reverting commits.
- Creates azure pipelines for new epics & feature, pipeline definition, agent pools, CICD & network resources, key vaults, Resources Groups & Access.
- Troubleshooting & Resolving issues and errors in azure pipelines & terraform, application with insights & log analytics.
- Updating & patching Virtual Machine for the CICD environment.
- Helping Team in Troubleshooting Issues & Resolving bugs.

PROCESS AUTOMATED

File System - Disk Usage Issues, Disk Extension, Remove Temp & Unused VM Binaries.

Compute - Automated Provisioning & De-Provisioning of VM, Create & Manage Workspace, Host Down & Ping Failure Events & Resolution, Complete **Health Checks**

REPORTING - Automated Reports In Excel & HTML

Active Directory - Managing Inactive Users, compliance, Access

ALERTS - Monitor a Metrics & Send the alert using SMTP Server

CERTIFICATES

AWS Certified

Cloud Practitioner | 2020

Microsoft Certified

Azure Fundamentals | 2021

HashiCorp Certified

Terraform Associate | 2021

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Expert

HINDI

Expert

FRENCH

Learning

PERSONAL DETAILS



+91 9425045390







RAGHUWANSHIDEEPAK79.DR @GMAIL.COM



Qtr. No. 06, Kotwali Campus, behind new Collectorate office building, Ashok Nagar, MP-473331

EXPERIENCE

Infrastructure Process Automation | Cloud DevOps Wipro | July 2018 - Nov 2020



- Collecting and understanding requirements by syncing with client.
- Analyzing the Standard Operating Procedure shared by client.
- ❖ Designing Logic & workflow for the solution & start development.
- Presented & Explained Design Documents to client for Approval.
- ❖ Developed Solution for Server Administrative Activities like Monitoring Performance, Health Checks, Vulnerability Fixes, Certificate Management, Azure-AD & Active Directory, 0365, Exchange, Pre & Post Checks Patch, Task scheduling and background job processing etc.
- ❖ Developed & Implemented Solution for Creating & Managing Workspace, Virtual Marching on AWS, Azure & VM Ware as per business requirements.
- Developed Solutions for reporting, Processing & Consolidating data from Various sources service-now or data Repository to one master report with Custom Dashboard in Excel or HTML based reports.
- Expert with Exception & Error Handling while Maintaining readable but detailed Error Logs for Quick Debugging & troubleshooting.
- ❖ Experience in provisioning Dev & Test Environment on Azure and AWS using Terraform & Configuration with ansible.
- ❖ Experience in Source code management by performing multiple operations on Gitlab and Repository Servers. Managed projects and Individual repositories of each project created multiple repos, Edited roles and permission for users based on access protocols.
- Experience in creating pipelines on Azure DevOps & Jenkins.
- **Experience** with Automation testing with selenium web driver.
- Hands on Experience in Containerization Environments with Docker and orchestrator with Kubernetes.
- knowledge on Quality and Analysis with SonarQube & JFrog.

DECLARATION

I hereby insist that the information provided is accurate to the best of my facts and belief.